Roi Driscoll - CV

Currently I work at Carwow — a car-comparison application which is designed to take the pain out of buying a new car. Here I am employed as a Front End Developer, where we work using Ruby on Rails and elm to bring our automotive experience to the masses.

It's rewarding to be working on a product that disrupts a process so many find painful, while working for a business who genuinely want to improve the experience of both the people buying cars, and the people selling them.

Before Carwow, I started my tech career at Makers Academy — You can read about that role here.

Experience

Carwow

Front End Developer - January 2018 - Present

- Currently on the team responsible for bringing used cars to the Carwow platform
- Although employed as a Front End Developer, currently working across the stack, using Ruby on Rails on the backend, and elm & Sass on the client side
- Responsible for encouraging adherence to our style guide
- Have led initiatives to improve communication between Developers and Designers in the organisation and implemented processes to achieve this goal
 - Introduced PR templates to the whole organisation as a way to improve consistency across the business when making Pull Requests
 - Designed and implemented a process to audit and catalogue changes to style guide components, in order to provide an effective changelog for the front end component library
- Co-organised a Craft Beer tasting session for the entire company

Feedback from Carwow:

"Roi is curious, passionate, great for team culture and has great product brain ... He challenges, contributes, leads and is very inclusive in team discussions ... Roi is quick to call me out on things and has the ability to truly see the broader picture. He raises things in retrospectives that few people would have considered. He also listens well and builds on ideas made by others.

Roi also is very keen to learn and to improve his skill set which is great. He doesn't insist on front-end cards and he asks questions when he doesn't understand ... he seems to be increasing his technical ability very quickly and it is great to see him grow in that regard. Roi wants what is best for the team which is a great trait." ~ Team Project manager

Makers Academy

Coach - July 2014 - December 2017

- Responsible for coaching 35+ students every 3 months
- Guide students through a challenge-based curriculum
- Facilitate daily stand ups and weekly retros
- Build independence and resourcefulness by building skills as opposed to spoon-feeding technical solutions to students
- Build and maintain student motivation during a very challenging time in their lives
- Monitor student feedback to identify points of confusion
- Run workshops, group code reviews, and individual 1:1 sessions to support students and alleviate confusion
- Review student code to gauge understanding and application of relevant principles and techniques
- Write engaging and relevant curriculum for both students and the general public
- Interview prospective students (and sometimes coaches)
- Run workshops for the general public to promote Makers Academy
- Volunteer time to work on Diversity & Inclusivity projects

Engineer - July 2014 - December 2017

- Responsible for a major overhaul of our website
- Pairing with senior engineers
- Daily stand ups (including feedback slots)
- Weekly Retros
- Write tickets for Kanban board (we prefer Waffle)
- · Point tickets in a weekly kickoff
- Adding new features to existing internal software tools
- Designing and building example apps for students

Feedback from Makers Academy:

"You single-handedly coach large cohorts. You do a wonderful job of caring for students, making them feel held and able to learn without fear. Your help as I've learnt to coach at Makers has made me a much better coach." ~ Mary Rose Cook (Coach)

Education

Makers Academy

London, UK - May 2014 - July 2014

- Highly intensive web development bootcamp
- · Focus on best practices revolving around coding
 - Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Design, SOLID design principles
- Focusing on important values and attitudes revolving around teamwork, pairprogramming, extreme programming and agile work methods

Other ways I spend my time

- I'm most happy when I'm playing my guitar, bass or singing.
- I love to read, and am currently chewing my way through Robert Jordan's Wheel of Time series.
- Currently learning (Brazilian) Portuguese, and Electronics (with the intention of making guitar effects pedals eventually.)
- Graphic Design makes me happy. I trained for years to spot great kerning, sublime colour palettes and consistent vertical rhythm from fifty paces.

Get in touch

- roi.driscoll@gmail.com
- Twitter
- Instagram